ライダーの宝具評価は
What's the rank of Rider's Noble Phantasm?
ギルガメッシュの「王の財宝」と同格
It's the same as Gilgamesh's Gate of Babylon.
つまり 評価規格外です
In other words, too powerful to be given a rank.
Things ended exactly as we'd planned.
確かに目論んだ通りの結末ではある
If we'd gone against Rider without knowing about his Noble Phantasm, we wouldn't have been able to defend against it.
もし予備知識のないまま ライダーと対決していたら
あの宝具に対処する術を見出せなかっただろう
ここから先は第二局目だ
This begins the second stage.
アサシンが収集した情報を基に
We will use the information Assassin gathered and mobilize Archer to defeat our enemies.
アーチャーを動員して敵を駆逐していく
A means to defeat Rider should reveal itself in the process.
ライダーに処する対策も その中で自ずと見えてくるだろう
Yes.
はい
マスターとしての勤め ご苦労だった
As a Master, your work is done.
Utw
Presents
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
恐らく昨夜の襲撃はアサシンの戦力を総動員したものと思われます
I believe last night's attack involved all the Assassins.
わかった
Understood.
ところで舞弥
By the way, Maiya.
新しい工房の件はどうなっている
Where are we with our new atelier?
明日の朝にはマダムたちを案内する予定です
Tomorrow morning, I will take Saber and Madam there.
あ 頼む
I see. Thank you.
はい それでは失礼します
No problem.
Goodbye, then.
遠坂邸に動きはなし
No activity at the Tohsaka residence.
初日のアサシン撃退以来
Tokiomi has been cooping himself up
since Assassin's attack on the first day.
時臣は穴熊を決め込んだまま
不気味なまでの沈黙
The silence is almost unsettling.
Miyama
間桐のマスターは見るからに無防備で襲撃は容易に見える
The Matou Master appears undefended, an easy target.
だが
But...
バーサーカーの不可解な特殊能力は
Berserker should probably be left alive due to his strange special ability, if only to distract Archer and Tohsaka.
アーチャーと遠坂を牽制する意味で
今は泳がせておくべきだろう
Miyama
ロード·エルメロイは再起不能のはずだが
New Town, East
Lord El-Melloi should be out of the running...
ランサーは脱落していない
But Lancer still remains.
新たなランサーのマスターが誰なのか
I'll need to discover his new Master's identity as soon as possible.
早急に確認する必要がある
Caster's location remains unknown.
Fuyuki City Serial Kidnappings and Murders:
No Progress in Investigations
キャスターの居所は依然として不明だが
昨夜もまた市内で数名の児童が失踪した
But last night, several children vanished from the city again.
奴らは何の憚りもなく狼藉を繰り返しているのだろう
They'll likely continue their atrocities without reserve.
Rider always travels with his Master in his flying Noble Phantasm.
ライダーは常にマスター共々飛行宝具で移動するため
追跡が困難
Tracking him is difficult.
一見豪放に見えるが
However largehearted he may seem, he is an extremely dangerous foe.
隙のない難敵だ
舞弥の報告にあった
I'm also concerned with the "Ionian Hetairoi" Noble Phantasm that Maiya reported.
「王の軍勢」と言う宝具のことも気になる
しかし それよりも
But, more importantly...
今度こそアサシンは完全消滅したと思っていいのでは
Can we assume that Assassin has been completely eliminated this time?
では そのマスターは
In that case, their Master...
If his plan was to work with Tohsaka
and use Assassin to spy on the others,
遠坂と組んでアサシンに諜報活動をさせる作戦ならば
ヤツは冬木教会から一歩も出てはいけなかったはずだ
then he wouldn't have taken a single step out of Fuyuki Church.
しかし 現実は違う
But that isn't what happened.
冬木ハイアットでの待ち伏せ
His ambush at the Fuyuki Hyatt...
アインツベルンの森への侵入
His attack in the Einzbern forest...
どちらも不可解な行動だ
Both of those are inexplicable.
もっとも ヤツの目的が僕だったとすれば筋は通る
However, it all makes sense if he was after me from the start.
だが何故だ 何故僕を狙う
But why?
Why pursue me?
一昨日の段階では
Two days ago, he should've had no way of knowing that I'm Saber's Master.
僕がセイバーのマスターであるという事実は知りえなかったはず
言峰綺礼 貴様は何者だ
Kotomine Kirei, who are you?
You seem in an excellent mood today, Archer.
今日はまた随分と上機嫌だな アーチャー
聖杯とやらの格は未だに見えぬが
I still see no worth in the Grail.
たとえガラクタであったとしても良しとしよう
But even if it's trash, that's fine.
オレはそれ以外の愉しみを見出した
I've found another form of entertainment.
In this age and world you've mocked
for being ugly and full of fakes?
贋物ばかりの醜悪な世界と嘲っていたこの時代で　か
That hasn't changed.
それは変わらぬ　だが　聖杯戦争とやらは最後まで見届ける気になった
However, I am now curious to see this Holy Grail War to the end.
I am fond of prideful individuals.
我はな　傲慢なる生を好む
Individuals who harbor grand ambitions, not knowing they aren't fit for the task.
器を弁えず大望を懐く者　そういう奴は見ているだけで我を愉しませる
Simply observing such people gives me great enjoyment.
There are two kinds of pride.
傲岸にも二種類あってな
One where you aren't fit for the task,
and one where your desires are too grand.
器が小さすぎる場合と　望みが大きすぎる場合
The former is commonplace stupidity...
前者は珍しくもない愚昧にすぎんが　後者はなかなか得難い珍種だ
...but the latter is rare and difficult to come by.
But they're identical in that they're both stupid, no?
いずれも愚かであることに違いはないではないか
Isn't rare stupidity far more precious than commonplace wisdom?
凡俗な賢しさよりも　希有な愚かしさの方が尊かろう
Those who have renounced their humanity for the
superhuman wishes they harbor despite being born human...
人に生まれ落ちながら　人ならざる領域の悲願を懐き
そのために人であることを捨てた者
I never grow weary of watching their grief and despair.
見ていて飽きぬのだ　そういう者の悲哀と絶望は
Kirei, you seem to be in a good mood yourself, for once.
綺礼 そういうお前こそ今日は珍しく上機嫌に見えるぞ
I am simply relieved.
ただの安堵だ
I've finally been freed from an unpleasant burden.
煩わしかった重荷から ようやく解放されたのでな
What happens to the Command Spells once they disappear?
消えた令呪というのは その後どうなるのだ
In theory, they return to the Grail.
理屈の上では 再び聖杯の元へと還る
The Holy Grail retakes the Command Spells from a Master who has lost his Servant and is thus out of the war.
サーヴァントを失ってマスターを失格となった者からは
聖杯がその令呪を回収するわけだ
And if a Servant loses its Master, the Grail will take those
unused Spells and redistribute them to a newly chosen Master.
そして もしマスターを喪ったサーヴァントが出てきた場合
聖杯は回収した未使用分の令呪を
新たに選んだマスターへと再配布する
The Command Spells remain in this world until they are used.
令呪は使用されない限り　現世に残り続け
Any that remain at the end are given to the judge.
最終的に残った物は監督役の手に委ねられることになる
So, depending on what happens from
now on, a new Master may yet appear?
では この後の展開次第では
新たなマスターが現れる可能性もあるということか
Yes.
そうだな だが聖杯に選ばれる適格者というのは
However, those that the Grail would
deem eligible are few in number.
そうそういるものではない
Thus, when a new Master is sought, the Grail tends to select those it has previously found suitable.
だから新たなマスターを捜す段になっても
結局聖杯は以前にマスターとして見込んだ人間を優先的に選ぶ傾向がある
What's wrong?
どうした 先を続けろよ 綺礼
Continue, Kirei.
That's the reason the Holy Church protects those who've dropped out of battle.
戦いから脱落したマスターを聖堂教会が保護するのも
それが理由だ
Should an empty place open among the remaining Masters,
彼らは残りのマスターに空席が生じた場合
there is a high probability that an ex-Master will receive the unused Command Spells.
かなりの確率で「使い残し」の令呪を再贈与される可能性が高い
This is why Grail War participants try to kill
enemy Masters rather than simply disable them.
だからこそ 聖杯戦争の参加者は
敵対するマスターを無力化するだけでなく殺そうとする
From that theory, Kirei, is there not a good chance that you will receive Command Spells yet again?
その理屈でいけば 綺礼
お前が再び令呪を得る可能性もまた大なのではないか
Impossible.
有り得ぬよ
If the Holy Grail chose me to support the Tohsaka camp like Tokiomi suggested, then I have fulfilled my duty.
聖杯が私に期待したのが 時臣師の説の通り
遠坂陣営の援護であったなら
もう私はその役目を果たし終えた
Tokiomi has already prepared a winning strategy for the remaining Masters and their Servants.
時臣師は既に全てのマスターとサーヴァントに対する必勝戦略を用意している
There's nothing more for me to do.
今さら私の出る幕はない
If you ask me, Tokiomi's hypotheses have been dubious from the start.
我に言わせれば　そもそもその時臣の仮説こそが疑わしい
He never struck me as worthy enough to
receive that much backing from the Grail.
あの男がそこまで聖杯に肩入れされるほどの器とは思えぬからな
I'm surprised you have such harsh words to say about your own Master.
自らのマスターに対し　よくもそこまで憚(はばか)りなく言えたものだ
Kirei, you seem to be sorely mistaken as to who serves whom in my relationship with Tokiomi.
綺礼　我と時臣との主従関係について大きく誤解しているようだな
He pays me every due respect as my subject and supplies me with mana as an offering.
時臣は我に臣下として礼を尽くし　供物として魔力を献上している
I answered his summons precisely because those were the terms of our pact.
そういう契約だからこそ我は彼奴の召喚に応じたのだ
What do you make of the Command Spells, then?
ならば令呪の存在はどう捉えている
I don't like them.
気に食わん
However, if a subject wishes to perform his duties better,
が　臣がよき臣下たらんと務めるならば
he must be willing to listen to criticism from time to time.
ときには諫言に耳を傾けるのも吝かではない
More importantly, Kirei.
それより綺礼　お前はさっき
You mentioned that the Assassins have fulfilled all their duties.
アサシンがすべて役目を果たしたと言っていたが
But what of the matter we discussed?
例の件はどうなった
Your interest in learning the motives of each Master in seeking the Grail?
各マスターが聖杯を求める動機を知りたいというやつか
Yes, that investigation is more or less completed.
まあ　それなりの調べは済んでいる
I should've had Assassin report his findings in person last night.
昨夜のうちにアサシン自身から報告させるべきだったな
That would've saved me the trouble of-
そうすれば説明の手間も
No, this is just fine.
いいや　これでいい
I'm not interested in what that shadow has to say.
あんな影ごときの言葉などに興味はない
Kirei, this report is meaningless unless it comes from your lips.
綺礼　これはお前の口を介して語られなければ意味のない報告だ
How does it feel to drive a car, Saber?
運転の感想はどう セイバー
It is indeed a splendid thing to steer.
実に素晴らしい乗り物です
I can't help but think what would've
happened if these had existed in my time.
これが私の時代にもあったらと思わずにはいられない
Irisviel, are you sure it's all right that I drive this vehicle?
アイリスフィール 私がこの乗り物を操ってよかったのですか
You seemed to enjoy the act of driving.
貴女が運転というものを楽しいんでいたように思いますが
It's fine.
いいのよ セイバーが喜んでくれれば 私も嬉しいわ
I'm happy if you are too.
I have to say, the skills of a Servant are amazing.
それにしても　サーヴァントのスキルって本当に凄いのね
This is your first time touching this machine, yet here you are, driving it perfectly.
初めて触る機械なのに あなたの運転って完壁よ
I find the sensation a little strange myself,
私も　いささか奇妙な感覚ではありますが
but it's like I'm employing skills that I was taught long ago.
まるで遠い昔に腕に覚え込ませた技術を振るっているような感じです
Rather than understanding it intellectually,
my body instinctively knows what to do next.
理屈で理解するというより　自然と次の操作が思い当たるのです
Still, is this a wise idea?
それにしても大丈夫なのですか
The estate to be our new base of operations lies right in the center of the battlefield.
新しい拠点にするという屋敷ですが　こんなにも戦場の直中にあるというのは
No need to worry about that.
その点は大丈夫
Fighting in secret is the great rule of the Grail War.
聖杯戦争は暗闘が大原則だもの
The Tohsakas and the Matous boldly fortify their bases within the city.
遠坂と間桐は堂々と市内に砦を構えているし
It's the Einzberns who are unusual for
building that castle in such a distant area.
あんな離れた立地に城を置いたアインツベルンの方が異質なぐらい
Since its location isn't known to the others,
むしろ所在を知られてないという点で　切嗣が用意したっていう新しい拠点の方が
the base that Kiritsugu prepared for us might be
more advantageous than the castle we've been using.
以前の城よりも有利かもしれないわ
This is yet another strange building.
また随分と不思議な建物ねぇ
From now on, this will be your base of operations.
お二人には 今日からここを行動の拠点としていただきます
Ah, if you could hand those to Saber.
それはセイバーが預かっておいて
Understood, Irisviel.
解りました アイリスフィール
舞弥 この鍵は何でしょうか
Maiya, what is this key?
It looks quite different from the others.
他のものとは随分違いますが
It's the key to the storehouse in the yard.
庭にある土蔵のものです
It's old, but I've personally confirmed that it's solidly built.
古いですが 立て付けに不安がないのは確認済みです
何の準備もされていないので
No preparations were made, so it might be somewhat lacking as a residence.
生活の場としては相応しくないかもしれませんが
That's fine.
構わないわ
とりあえず 雨風さえ凌げるなら文句は言いません
I have no complaints as long as it shelters us from the rain and wind.
Well then, Saber.
さて それじゃあ セイバー 新居の点検といきますか
Let's explore our new home!
Okay.
そうですね
I think this is supposed to be like one of Japan's haunted houses.
この国なりの幽霊屋敷って趣かしらね
I'm sure all the hallways have wooden floors, while the rooms
are floored with woven grass and have partitions made of paper!
きっと廊下は板張りで 干し草を編み固めた床に
紙の間仕切りで部屋を分けてるのよ
I did say once that I wanted to see a Japanese mansion.
昔日本のお屋敷を見てみたいって話したの
Maybe Kiritsugu remembered!
切嗣は憶えていてくれたのかしら
Was it not what you expected?
期待していたほどの内容ではありませんでしたか
No, I enjoyed touring it.
それは堪能できたんだけどね
But this isn't really an ideal base for a Mage.
魔術師の拠点として考えると ちょっと難しいのよね ここ
The magical fields are well-laid, but to establish an atelier here...
結界の敷設はいいんだけど
工房の設置がね
The design is too open to the outside, so mana will be readily lost.
こうも開放的な造りだと 魔力が散逸しすぎるわ
I would've preferred a room walled off with stone or clay.
できれば石か土で密閉された部屋が欲しかったんだけれど
This is ideal!
ここなら理想的
It's a little small, but I can craft my spells here just as well as back at the castle.
ちょっと手狭だけれど
ここならお城と同じ要領で術式を組んでも大丈夫ね
Simply inscribing a magic circle here
should be enough to make this place mine.
とりあえず魔法陣を敷いておくだけで 私の領域として固定化できそう
Let's get started.
さっそく準備に取りかかりましょうか
Will you please help me, Saber?
悪いけど セイバー
手を貸してくれる
We'll draw a magic circle there, six feet in diameter.
あの場所に 六フィート径で魔法陣を描くの
Okay.
はい
I'll need your help once we start placing the mercury.
水銀の調合からお願いすることになるわ
I'll tell you how to distribute it, so don't worry.
配分は私の方で指示するから 大丈夫
Saber, can you bring me the ingredients we left in the trunk?
それじゃあ セイバー
車に積んである資材を持ってきてくれる
Irisviel, I'd like to ask you something.
アイリスフィール ひとつ伺いますが
It seems that you've been careful not to touch anything today.
今日の貴女は 何か物に触れることを慎重に避けている節がある
Am I imagining things?
私の気のせいでしょうか
Driving the car, holding the keys...
車の運転 鍵の扱い
I wouldn't have worried about small matters like that.
その程度なら気にするまでもないと思っていましたが
But you aren't even performing your own magic.
肝心の魔術の実演まで やはり ご自身でなさろうとしない
It's important that you tell me in advance if you aren't feeling well.
もしも体調の不安なら 事前にそうと教えてもらわなければ
It's my duty to protect you when necessary.
いざとなれば私は貴女の身を守るという務めがある
That's why I need to know.
それ相応の配慮が必要になります
I'm sorry.
御免なさいね
You're right. This isn't something I should hide from you.
たしかに隠してどうこうなるものでもなかったわ
Hold out your hand.
手を出して
Saber, I'm going to squeeze your hand with all my strength.
セイバー いまから私は精一杯の力であなたの手を握るわね
Ready?
Yes, go ahead...
ええ どうぞ
アイリスフィール
Irisviel?
I'm not playing around.
ふざけてるわけじゃないのよ
This is all the strength I can muster.
今の私には これで精一杯なの
Tugging your fingers is the most I can do.
指先に引っかけたりするのがせいぜいで
Holding them or gripping them is beyond me.
握ったり摘んだりはとても無理
Getting dressed this morning was really tough, too!
朝 着替えるのにもかなり苦労しちゃった
Wh-What could be wrong?
い 一体どうしたのです
Are you hurt?
どこか怪我でも
ちょっと体調が優れなくてね
I'm not feeling very well, so I've severed my sense of touch.
触覚を遮断してるの
五感の一つを封じるだけでも霊格をかなり抑えられるから
Shutting down just one of the five senses
lets me suppress the spirituality quite a bit,
so that it won't interfere with anything else that I do.
他の行動には支障をきたさなくて済むってわけ
I guess the ability to do such things is an advantage of being a homunculus.
こういう融通が利くのってホムンクルスの強みよね
It can't be that simple!
そんな簡単に済ませていい話ではないでしょう
What exactly is wrong with your body, anyway?
そもそも身体の不調というのはいったい何なのです
Do you require treatment?
手当てが必要なのでは
忘れているかもしれないけど
You may have forgotten, but I'm not a normal human.
私は普通の人間ではなくてよ
風邪をひいたからって医者に診てもらうってわけにもいかないの
When I'm ill, a doctor cannot treat me.
Well, I guess you can say the problem
stems from defects in my construction.
この不調は まあ 私の構造的欠陥とでもいうべきものだから
Don't worry about it.
大丈夫
Though, it does mean I'll need you
to help me with all kinds of things.
そうは言っても色々とセイバーには迷惑をかけちゃうのよね
今日みたいに もう車の運転はあなたに任せるしかないし
I'll need you to drive my car like you did today and help me with my magical rituals.
魔術の儀式にも 手を貸してもらわなきゃならないわ
I'm sorry.
済まないんだけど
But I'll be relying on you, my knight.
宜しく頼むわね
私の騎士様
Absolutely.
勿論です
And I apologize for prying. Please forgive me.
こちらこそ余計な詮索をして申し訳ありませんでした
お許しを
It's fine, don't worry.
いいのいいの
Well, let's quickly get that circle crafted.
さあ それより手早く陣の敷設を済ませちゃいましょう
My condition should improve a little if I rest in a
magic circle properly connected to local ley lines.
きちんと地脈に繋いだ魔法陣で休息すれば
私の具合も ちょっと好転するはずだから
Understood.
わかりました
I'll bring the ingredients in.
それでは資材を取ってきます
Neither Lancer's Master nor Rider's Master
have wishes they'd like the Holy Grail to grant.
ランサーのマスター　ライダーのマスターについては
べつだん聖杯に託するだけの願望があるわけでもなく
They simply seek victory to bring them glory as Magi.
ただ魔術師としての栄誉のために勝利を求めている
As for Caster's Master, he doesn't
even understand what the Grail is.
キャスターのマスターに至っては
そもそも聖杯の何たるかさえ理解していない
ただの快楽殺人の延長として　聖杯戦争に加わっているにすぎない
He's taking part in the Grail War just so he can continue killing people for fun.
As for Berserker's Master, he seeks the rather naive act of atonement.
バーサーカーのマスターは
何とも青臭いことに贖罪を求めている
Because he had once severed all ties with the Matou family,
自身がいったん間桐家から逐電したことで
the younger Tohsaka daughter was taken in
to be groomed as the next Matou family head.
代わりに次期当主に祭り上げられることになった遠坂の次女を
Yet, he is now demanding that the girl be set free.
今になって解放しろという要求をしているようだ
He has been given the task of winning the Holy Grail to secure his end of the bargain.
そのための取引材料として　聖杯を勝ち取るという使命を課されている
In addition, he appears to have some sort of past relationship with Tokiomi's wife.
しかもどうやら　時臣氏の奥方とも過去の因縁があるらしい
In a sense, his motives are probably the most
vulgar and banal among the five competing Masters.
ある意味では五人の敵対マスターの中で
もっとも卑俗で凡庸な動機の持ち主といえるかもしれんな
What is it?
どうした　続けろ　綺礼
Continue, Kirei.
セイバーのマスターは
Saber's Master...
It appears he was merely hired to achieve the Einzberns'
long-held, delusional dream of manifesting the Holy Grail.
アインツベルンの昔年の妄執
つまり聖杯の降臨を実現させたいという悲願のために
金で雇われただけのようだ
How very disappointing.
期待はずれもいいところだな
He's just another mongrel.
所詮は雑種
They're all a bunch of mediocrities with utterly uninteresting reasons for seeking my treasure.
どいつもこいつも凡俗なばかりで何の面白味もない
くだらぬ理由で我が宝を求めおって
That's all you have to say after
making me go through all that trouble?
これだけ他人を煩わせておいて
出てきた感想がそれか
Think of all the effort I wasted.
徒労に付き合わされた身にもなってみろ
Effort you wasted?
徒労だと
何を言うか 綺礼
What are you talking about, Kirei?
The hard work of you and the Assassins has paid off splendidly.
お前とアサシンの骨折りには充分な成果があったではないか
Are you mocking me, King of Heroes?
私をからかっているのか 英雄王
You don't understand?
解せぬか まあ無理もない
I can't blame you.
You're a man who doesn't even know what he finds pleasurable.
己の愉悦の在処さえ見定められぬ男だからな
A soul naturally seeks pleasure, consciously or not.
自覚がなくとも
魂というものは本能的に愉悦を追い求める
That inner desire is expressed through one's interests and concerns.
そういう心の動きは 興味 関心として表に現れる
In other words, Kirei, having you talk about what you make of
the things you've seen and heard already has plenty of meaning.
故に 綺礼
お前が見聞きし 理解した事柄を
お前の口から語らせたことには
既に充分な意味があるのだ
What you speak of at greatest length is what interests you the most.
もっとも多くの言葉を尽くした部分が
お前の興味を惹きつけた出来事に他ならぬ
First, let us rule out the man you deliberately avoided talking about.
まずお前が意図的に言葉を伏せた人物については除外しよう
自覚のある関心はただの執着でしかない
An interest you're aware of is nothing but obsession.
So, which of the remaining four did you speak of most passionately?
さてそうなると
残る四人のマスターのうち
お前が最も熱を込めて語った一人は誰だったか
Berserker's Master.
バーサーカーのマスター
Kariya, wasn't it?
たしか雁夜とか言ったかな
綺礼よ この男については随分と子細に報告してくれたではないか
Kirei, you spoke of him in great detail.
The circumstances surrounding him are complicated.
事情の入り組んでいる人物だ
それなりの説明を要したというだけのことだが
He simply required additional explanation.
Wrong.
ふん 違うな
He was the only one you ordered Assassin to investigate to such a
degree that you could understand those "complicated circumstances".
お前はこの男についてのみ
入り組んだ事情が見えてくるほどの調査をアサシンに強要してしまったのだ
And this was all due to your unconscious interest.
お前自身の無自覚な興味によってな
I admit I made a judgmental error.
判断のミスは認める
It's true that Matou Kariya poses no threat in the long term, and so was not worth the attention.
たしかに間桐雁夜は長い目で見れば脅威ではなく
注目には値しない
My overestimation of his abilities has invited your pointless prying into me.
私が彼を過大評価したことで
結果的にお前の余計な詮索を招いてしまった
That's your response?
そうきたか
では万が一の奇跡と僥倖が重なって
Then imagine for me a scenario in which Berserker and his Master survive until the very end by chance and fortune.
バーサーカーとそのマスターが
最後まで生き永らえるシナリオを想定してみろ
Can you picture what would happen then?
その時何が起こるか
お前には思い描けるか
なあ  綺礼よ
Hey, Kirei.
もういい加減に気付いてもいいのではないか
Isn't it about time you realized the
true meaning of what I've been asking?
この問いかけの本質的な意味に
Tell me, Archer.
教えろ アーチャー
What is the point of picturing Matou Kariya's victory?
間桐雁夜の勝利を仮想することに
一体どういう意味がある
No point.
ないさ 意味など微塵もない
None at all.
Come on now, don't be so mad.
おいおい そう怖い顔するな
Think about it.
考えてもみろよ
The fact that Kotomine Kirei never recognized the pointlessness in such speculation.
その思弁の無意味さに ついぞ言峰綺礼が気付かなかったという事実
Don't you think there's clear, unshakable meaning to it?
そこには明白にして揺るがぬ意味があるとは思わぬか
説明しろ アーチャー
Explain it to me, Archer.
If you'd been given the same question regarding another Master,
もし仮に 他のマスターについて同じ課題を与えられていれば
you would've immediately realized its
pointlessness and rejected it as a waste of time.
お前は早々にその無意味さに気付き
詮ないものとして一蹴していたはずだ
But that was not how it went with Kariya.
ところが雁夜についてはそうはならなかった
You abandoned your usual sharp wits and wasted your time in pointless thought.
お前は平時の無駄のない思考を放棄し
延々と益体のない妄想に耽っていた
You forgot it was pointless.
無意味さの忘却 苦にならぬ徒労
You didn't mind the effort was wasted.
In other words, you clearly enjoyed it.
即ち 紛れもなく「遊興」だ
Celebrate, Kirei.
祝えよ 綺礼
You've understood what entertainment is at last.
お前はついに娯楽の何たるかを理解したのだぞ
Entertainment?
娯楽 即ち愉悦だと
Pleasure, in other words?
Exactly.
然り
There is nothing in Matou Kariya's fate that could bring a man pleasure.
間桐雁夜の命運に 人の悦たる要素など皆無だ
His life is nothing but suffering and tragedy.
彼は生き長らえる程に痛みと嘆きを積み重ねるしかない
For him, a quick death would be a blessing.
いっそ早々に命を落としたほうがまだ救われる人物だ
Kirei, why must you see pleasure in such a narrow sense?
綺礼よ なぜそう悦を狭義に捉える
Where is the contradiction in treating
suffering and tragedy as forms of pleasure?
痛みと嘆きを悦とすることに
何の矛盾があるというのだ
Pleasure doesn't just come in one form.
愉悦の在り方に定型などない
You're confused because you don't understand that.
それが解せぬから迷うのだ お前は
This isn't something that can be forgiven!
それは許されることではない
英雄王 貴様のような人ならざる魔性なら
King of Heroes, an inhuman demon such as yourself
might find the suffering of others sweet to the taste.
他者の辛苦を蜜の味とするのも頷ける
But that is the soul of a sinner!
だが それは罪人の魂だ
An evil that must be punished!
罰せられるべき悪徳だ
This is all the more true in the path of faith that I follow!
わけても この言峰綺礼が生きる信仰の道においてはな
So that's why you define pleasure itself to be a sin.
故に愉悦そのものを罪と断じてきたか
It's incredible how far you've managed to warp it.
よくそこまで屈折できたな
You're an unbelievably interesting man.
つくづく面白い男だよ お前は
This pain...
この痛みは
Ooh.
Just as I'd thought.
ほほう やはりオレの予想通りか
But faster than I'd expected.
それにしても随分とまた早かったな
Impossible...
馬鹿な
No Servant has yet been released from their contract.
契約にはぐれたサーヴァントなどいないというのに
Why has a new Master been chosen?
なぜ 新たにマスターが選ばれるのだ
It looks like the Holy Grail expects
great things from Kotomine Kirei.
どうやら 聖杯は言峰綺礼によほどの期待を託している様子だな
Kirei, you should attend once again to the Grail's summons.
綺礼 お前もまた聖杯の求めに応じるへきだ
Without a doubt, you have a reason to seek this wish-granting device.
紛れもなくお前には願望機を求めるだけの理由がある
I have a reason to seek the Grail?
私が
聖杯を
If it really is an omnipotent wish-granting device,
それが真に万能の願望機であるならば
聖杯はお前自身にすら理解の及ばぬ
then it can give shape to the wish even you
don't understand in the depths of your heart.
心の奥底の願望をそのままに形を与えて示すことだろう
So you're saying I should use the wish-granting device as a means to infer my wish, since I don't know what it is.
願望の何たるかを知り得ぬが故に
願望機そのものを手段とし
結末を占わせようというのか
But that can only happen after I've destroyed six other wishes.
だがそれは 六つの願望を殺し潰した後に
初めて手に入る結末だ
If I seek the Grail for my own desire...
私個人の要求で聖杯を求めるならば
それは己が師をも敵に廻す ということになる
...it'll mean becoming my teacher's enemy.
Then you'd better find yourself a strong Servant if you're going to fight me.
せいぜい強力なサーヴァントを見繕うことだな
このオレと争うのであれば
But that's only if you manage to steal a Servant currently bound by contract to another Master in the first place.
そもそも前提として
お前は他のマスターとの契約下にあるサーヴァントを
奪い取ることから始めなければならないわけだ
In that case...
ならば いっそ
No, I won't say it.
いや 言うまい
Everything from here onwards is up to you.
ここから先は万事がお前次第なのだから
求めるところを為すがいい
Do as you desire.
それこそが娯楽の本道だ
That is the true meaning of entertainment.
Entertainment leads to pleasure...
そして娯楽は愉悦を導き
And pleasure will lead you to happiness.
愉悦は幸福の在処を指し示す
Your path is now clear, Kirei.
道は示されているぞ 綺礼
もはや惑うまでもないほど明確にな
So clear that there's no need to hesitate.
Episode 12
The Grail's Invitation
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
I shall be the first to strike!
一番槍はいただくぞ
This would be the perfect opportunity to defeat him.
仕留めるなら 今が絶好のチャンスね
Let's finish this.
決着をつけるぞ
I'm sure the world is filled with God's love.
きっとこの世界は神様の愛に満ちてるよ
Now let us once again raise the flag of salvation!
今再び我らは救世の旗を掲げよう
Next Episode
The Forbidden Banquet